Joel Reynolds

IT Consultant | Desktop Support | Technical Support Tech - Seeking New Opportunity

McKinney, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Joel-Reynolds/326d1d062ecf035f

Brings 6 years of accomplishment in the information technology field, providing outstanding technical support, troubleshooting, and consistently achieving stellar client satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Consultant

Reynolds IT Consulting - May 2016 to Present

- Perform troubleshooting and repair, setting up networks, printers, computers, cell phones, smart home equipment
- Have grown a loyal client base through referrals and customer relationship management
- Independently create solutions to new and unique challenges as the client's problem solver
- Recognized as a preferred provider of computer and network remote maintenance
- Decrypted a locked hard drive that was TrueCrypt-encrypted by the previous IT manager for the president at Praxis Healthcare Solutions, LLC
- Succeeding at expanding the business' scope of work to include data recovery, lessons, and to work with small-medium sized businesses

Advanced Repair and Consultation Agent

Best Buy - Geek Squad - January 2015 to December 2016

- · Achieved unrivaled revenue performance by ranking top in revenue-per-minute every month
- Received the "MVP" award for implementing a new standard to the Geek Squad's troubleshoot and repair process
- Earned the highest positive feedback for client-facing technical repairs and support
- Responsible for creating service orders, troubleshooting and resolving issues (networking, software confliction) while engaging with the client, and escalating service orders
- Performed repairs ranging from replacing a hard drive to replacing a laptop's motherboard
- Served as the endpoint of escalation for non-hardware related issues such as Microsoft Office, Windows updates and drivers, infections, encryption, data backup and recovery
- Obtained Advanced Repair Agent Certification
- Considered the "go-to" agent for escalated and difficult technical problems and repairs

Corporate Account Manager, Business-to-business

Tiger Direct - Kingston, JM - June 2013 to January 2014

- Responsible business development with TigerDirect's business-to-business channel, including corporations, retail stores, government, school districts, and other resellers
- Built corporate accounts, such as Verizon's Southeast corporate and retail channel
- Utilized the "power of people" by working with every potential business partner, such as product account managers (Dell, Lenovo, Kingston, etc.), leasing agencies (VAR, Navistas Leasing Corp.), logistics (UPS, YRC Freight), accounts payable, customer service, technical support, and competitors with mutual accounts (Ingram Micro, D&H)

Microsoft Advisor

Best Buy - October 2011 to May 2013

- · Highest in revenue and profitability of the store at Mobile's two most important launch dates
- Built rapport with customers, resulting in their purchasing complete solutions
- Continually kept up-to-date with changing technology and surpassed sales goals
- Achieved highest in revenue and revenue-by-hour in the district for December 2012
- Incorporated all aspects of Mobile, Computer and Tablet Sales Consultant with high emphasis on training, leading, and achieving store goals
- Connected Business Group Consultant (Wireless, Computers & Tablets)
- Created, maintained, and upgraded customer accounts for cellular devices with Verizon, AT&T, and Sprint

EDUCATION

Collin County Community College 2010 to 2011

Richland Community College 2007

LINKS

http://reynoldsit.com

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS

- Effective communication to clients, regardless of their technical experience
- Exceptional and exponentially growing technical aptitude
- Keen ability to analytically view a problem and efficiently resolve it
- Building and repairing PC's, laptops, phones, tablets, and NAS systems
- Windows server 2012 and 2016, managing computers via local users and group policies editor
- Broad familiarity with networking hardware by Cisco, Netgear, Ubiquti, ASUS, Trendnet
- · Manage networks via active directory, emails through exchange server and Microsoft office 365
- Install patch panels, troubleshoot printers, webhosting
- G-Suite (formerly Google apples), Google Docs, Admin, and more
- NAS systems, networks (LAN, WAN, WLAN, SAN, VPN)
- Operating systems: Windows, Windows server, Apple OS, and their mobile counterparts as well as, Android, Chrome OS, Linux, Ubuntu, Tails, Kali
- Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word, Outlook, PowerPoint, Excel, Publisher, OneDrive, and OneNote)